# **TRAVIS WAY**

DENVER, CO TRAVISWAY2@GMAIL.COM (941)704-6072

# **OBJECTIVE**

I am an Oracle certified Software Developer capable of back end or full stack development. I am currently seeking a software development position.

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a Java Developer with 2 years of experience in Development and 2 years experience in Systems Administration. I am currently studying at The Skill Distillery to further my knowledge of Java, HTML, CSS, Spring, Maven, Bootstrap, JSP, SQL, Angular and JavaScript. I work well in a team environment and alone. I am able to prioritize and self-motivate to accomplish assigned goals and take initiative to resolve potential problems before they occur. I am a quick study and quickly gain understanding of new systems and concepts.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer Github Personal Website August 2016 - Present

I am currently polishing my craft(Full Stack Development) at the Skill Distillery. I have developed several applications using Java, AWS, JSP, Spring, HTML, CSS, and BootStrap including but not limited to, a 'Presidents' WebApp that based off a csv file, reads, parses, and gives the info into a JSP webpage and makes it searchable. That project and many others I am currently working on can be seen on my on my website with the link above.

# System Administrator/Software Developer . February 2016 – April 2017 Meridian Asset Services, St Petersburg FL

- Strong knowledge of OOP.
- Developed several applications using my knowledge of Java, AWS, JSP, and Spring MVC, and PowerShell.
- Using Java, I developed an application that would separate large Pdf files into individual page files which saved the company time, money, resources.
- Responsible for the maintenance and support of all infrastructure and support systems.
   This includes end user support and the installation, maintenance and support of computers, servers, software, peripherals, telecommunications equipment, network switches, and routers.
- Administered, and maintained Windows Servers 2008/2012, Active Directory.
- Created and built desktops to user's required criteria.
- Provide technical assistance and support for 120 users with incoming queries and issues related to computer systems, software, and hardware.

#### Skills

Strong knowledge of OOP and OOD.

Strong understanding of the Java programming language

Working Knowledge of C, C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, JDBC, Angular.

Currently working at learning more Full Stack development principles.

Strong understanding of the Spring framework.

Advanced understanding of networking, system maintenance.

# United States Army, Iraq / South Korea / Egypt /Ft Bliss, TX

#### Iraq

- Team Commander/Assistant Convoy Commander
- Promoted from Driver, to Team commander, to Assistant convoy commander while deployed to Iraq.
- Oversaw the deployment of 3 million dollars of equipment and the safety and wellbeing of 20 soldiers.
- Honorably discharged in 2012(DD214 provided upon request)

# Korea/Ft Bliss

- As a Patriot Missile Fire Operator and diagnosed/fixed any technical issues that arose with the Computer Systems.
- Was in charge of the welfare of 5 soldiers, as well as following procedures to successfully defend the United States and its allies while serving in Egypt, South Korea and several military posts throughout the United States. I developed the technical knowledge I now possess from training I received to operate the patriot missile system.

# **EDUCATION**

High School Diploma – Lakewood Ranch High School Studied Mathematics at St Petersburg College Studied Full Stack Development at the Skill Distillery May 2017-September 2017 Completed – May 2001 March 2013 – December 2015

# **ACTIVITIES & AWARDS**

Army Achievement Medal Good Conduct Medal Oracle Certification, Java 8 Programmer